

Kiran Uddhav Marathe
Assistant Manager
(Finance & Accounts Department)

Phone: +91-8975-737-737

Email: marathekiran27@gmail.com

#### Profile

Professional with 10+ Years of experience in the field of Finance & Taxation. I want to seek a responsible and challenging position in finance department of organization which will utilize my abilities, courage, knowledge & skills in the best interest of the organization. I will also try to discover newer ideas for performing tasks in a better and efficient way thereby enhancing corporate functions and identity of the organization. Building professional relationships with colleagues and seniors. Time management is the key factor of my work and I do all necessary actions to complete all tasks on time and to cater with huge volume of work. Ability to work independently and in Team. Self-Motivated Professional.

#### **Educational Qualification**

Bachelor of Laws
(LL. B) Pune University
Graduated in 2017

<u>Diploma In Taxation</u> <u>Law (D.T.L)</u> Pune University Completed in 2013 <u>Master of Commerce</u>

(M. Com) Pune University Graduated in 2012

GDC&A Maharashtra Board

Completed in 2011

#### Certifications

MS-CIT, Tally 7.2, 8.0, 8.1, 9.0 ERP, G.C.C.E English Typing Examination 30 W.P.M.

# Major Achievement's

 Received award of Champion of the moth for November 19 & July 20 for receiving the huge refund from income tax department after closure of faceless E-assessment.

## Work Experience

Organization	Sahyadri Hospitals Private Limited (Dec 2017 - Till Date)
Functional Area	Finance, Income Tax, Goods & Service Tax (GST), Way Bill System, Sales
	Tax.
Role	Assistant Manager (Finance & Accounts Department)

## Responsibilities

## 1. Income Tax:

- Handling the Income Tax assessment (including E-Assessments).
- Working on Income Tax audit with preparation of reports of 3CA & 3CD with required Annexures.
- Working on Income Tax related entries required to be posted in books.
- Daily monitoring the Income Tax website for tracking the Notices received for faceless assessments.
- Updating the Assessment tracker regularly for reporting to senior authority in company.
- Handling the compliance of Form 60 & 61(including tracking of cash collection above 2lac as per provision of income tax act).
- Handling the application of lower rate TDS deduction application u/s 197 of income tax. Communicate with insurance companies,
   TPA'S and corporates for getting the impact of TDS deduction @ lower rate.
- Working on Quarterly reconciliation of TDS as per books V/s. 26AS.
- Handling the application u/s 17 (2) of income tax for receiving the periodic approval from income tax authorities.
- Application of Form 15CA / CB as per the applicability for foreign payments.
- Trust related application for 80G and 12A registration on income tax portal.

## 2. TDS & TCS (Tax deduction and collection at source):-

- TDS & TCS monthly liability working including processing the e-payment.
- Quarterly return filling of TDS & TCS.
- Quarterly Form 16A generation through TRACES portal and ensure the distribution of same with in prescribed time with doctors and service providers.
- Rectification in TDS returns through TRACES (if required).
- TDS payment for section 194IA- Purchase of immovable property (Monthly tracking).
- Eqalisation levy compliance for e-commerce transactions on monthly basis with annual return.
- Currently handling the compliances required to be done for new amendment of Section 206AB, 206CCA & 194Q.
- Monitoring the TDS deduction on expenses booked (TDS payable reconciliation), to avoid the disallowance on expenses in tax audit.

## 3. GST (Goods & Service Tax):-

- Handling the changes required in core filed and non-core field on GST portal.
- Working on monthly return filling of GST in form GSTR-3B and GSTR-1.
- Working on monthly ITC (input tax credit) with reconciliation with GSTR-2B and GSTR-2A.
- Handling the RCM (reversed charge mechanism) tracker for finalization of monthly liability.
- Preparation of GSTR-9and GSTR-9C data for GST Audit.
- Working on issue of PVDN (Purchase voucher debit note) to the suppliers and collecting the CN (Credit Notes).
- Tracking the sale of B2B transaction for avoiding the non-compliance of E-invoice through GST portal.
- Handling E-way bill related transaction with monitoring the inward and outward register of E-way bill portal.

#### 4. FAR (Fixed Assets Register) :-

- From last year F.Y 2020-21, handling the fixed asset register of company.
- Regularly providing the WDV and asset sale related entries to various unit locations for booking purpose.
- Monitoring the transaction of asset disposal and asset scrap.
- Working on providing the monthly deprecation working for MIS.
- Handling the inter unit asset transfer movement.
- Physical asset verification (annual task) and collection of reports with necessary approvals.
- Annual booking of depreciation with preparation of schedules required for Annual report.

# 5. Other Task:-

- Supporting in Internal, Statutory Audit and other compliance related checking as per company's standard practices.
- Working on annual Bonus provision for company level.
- Handling the actuarial valuation of gratuity and leave encashment as per the company policy and get the valuation report from the consultant for recording the provision while annual closure of books.
- Monthly working on the report of transaction with MSME (Micro, Small and Medium enterprises) to avoid interest chargeable for delay payment of MSME registers vendors.
- Handling due diligence for Direct and Indirect tax which includes preparation of required report and data submission on cloud base data bank.
- Monitoring the RPT (Related Party Transactions) with subsidiaries and KMP (key management personals) on regular basic along with preparation of notes to accounts for statutory audit and collection of balance confirmations from related parties.
- Handling notes on contingent liability disclosure for annual report with regular monitoring.
- Handling the annual activity of record destruction across units, as per the company policy.
- Handling the own cloud (data bank) of company for uploading the agreements on portal those are readily available and
  accessible to users, as and when required.

- Working on software and system customization required as per the new amendments of direct and indirect tax.
- Conducting the awareness sessions across the units for new amendments of direct and indirect tax.

Organization	Thermax Ltd. (August 2015 toDec 2017)
Functional Area	Finance, Sales Tax, GST.
Role	Sales Tax Support

## Responsibilities

- Worked on GST Registration process, filling of GST Returns in form GSTR-3B and GSTR-1
- Verification of tax invoices to process C, H and F Forms applications.
- Invoice verification as per the company's standard compliance practices to minimize irregularity observed in various internal and external checking authorities.
- Professional Tax monthly return filling after verification of data.
- Company level consolidation of WCTDS returns data and filling of return.
- Consolidation of quarterly data relating to interstate purchases to process Form C application.
- Verification of H Form purchases by linking of bill of lading to process applications.
- Verification of Branch Transfer invoices to process monthly F Form applications.
- As per the requirements of various divisions handling tax master of thermax to open the tax codes in Oracle for booking of
  invoices in correct tax code.
- Assisting my superior in documentation related to monthly VAT/CST returns for the states Karnataka, Tamilnadu and Madhya Pradesh.
- Communication and coordination with various Sales Tax Authorities in sales tax office.
- Assistance to superiors in related tasks as and when required.
- Supporting Divisional, Internal, Statutory Audit and other compliance related checking as per company's standard practices.
- Maintain & update Oracle ERP on regular basis.
- Sharing knowledge with team mates for any new trends in taxation and compliance

Organization	V.M. NAVANDAR & CO. Tax Consulting Firm (May 2010 to August2015)
Functional Area	Income Tax, Sales Tax, Service Tax, TDS, Internet Banking
Role	Income Tax and Sales Tax Practitioner

#### Responsibilities

- Processing the new assesses PAN card application.
- Verification of documents and process the VAT, CST, PTRC and PTEC registration application on Mahavat Site for taking registration. (Voluntary or Exceeding Turnover)
- Calculation of VAT and CST on monthly, quarterly and half yearly to make payment and to fill the returns before the due dates.
- Calculation of Service Tax and filling of Service Tax Returns (ST3)
- Verification of documents and process online application of ROF (registration of firm)
- Preparation of documents as per the requirement of sales tax authorities to attend the hearing of assessments.
- Handling the regular Sales Tax assessments, appeals of various firms.
- Discussed the issues relating to assessments with the higher authorities to take their opinions about it, along with that regularly
  doing the case studies and maintain the copies of order passed by various appellate authorities to use it in regular assessment
  work.
- Regular studies of new circulars and notifications received by government authorities for implementation.
- Carried out VAT audits starting from primary checking of various documents and statistical data provided, preparing various statements of revealing how the facts and figures are arrived at and filling in Form No 704.
- Verification of tax invoices to process C Forms applications.
- Income Tax working, making payments of self assessment tax and filing of returns (individuals, proprietary businesses, partnerships, and Pvt. Ltd. Companies)
- Preparation of Trading, Profit and Loss Accounts and Balance sheets.
- Preparation of TDS statements, making payments and filling of returns on quarterly basic and visit to NSDL office for filling.
- As per client's requirement worked in preparation of project reports.
- Preparation of Financial Statements, Documents, Data Sorting, Formulating.
- Preparation of Documents, Letter Heads, Communication with customers, bankers, suppliers etc.
- Preparation of PPT presentation.
- Working with Tally 7.2, 9.0, 9.0 ERP.
- Making online payments of thousands of client through internet banking.
- Clear command on Income Tax, Sales Tax software's like Monarch (I-Tax) & Sinewave (Vat Express)

#### Personal Information:

Date of Birth: December 27, 1989

Marital Status: Married

Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi

Interests: Listening music, Travelling, Learning new thing